Guide to the Charles Benton Power papers 1870-1971
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Charles Benton Power papers
1870-1971
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 55a
Power, Charles Benton, 1868-1953
10 linear feet of shelf space
Charles Power (1868-1953) was a Helena, Montana, attorney and businessman, and son of Thomas C. Power. Collection (bulk, 1870s-1950s) includes incoming correspondence (1881-1953), diaries (1929-1949), subject files, and miscellany. There are also subgroups for family members and for several businesses of Power's.
Charles Benton Power was born in Dubuque, Iowa, on November 9, 1868, the only child of Thomas C. Power and his wife Mary Flanagan Power. While Charles was still an infant, his father moved the family to Fort Benton, Montana, where he established a steamboat and mercantile empire. The family moved to Helena in 1878.
Charlie, as he was always known, graduated from Georgetown College in Washington, D.C., in 1888. He got a second bachelor's degree from Columbia College in New York in 1891 and a law degree from Columbia Law School in 1893. He practiced law in Helena for two years, before going to work in his father's enterprises, including T.C. Power and Brother, the American National Bank, and the various ranches. Eventually he took over management of these companies, and became president on his father's death in 1923.
In December 1902, Charles Power married Mabel Larson, niece and adopted daughter of Peter and Margaret Larson. The Powers had three children: Margaret Power Drum Carrick (b. 1904), Benton Power (b. 1907), and Jane Power Tobin (b. 1912). Mabel Power died July 4, 1918. In 1943 Charles Benton Power married Pauline McGuire Ely. He died November 15, 1953, six days after his 85th birthday.
Papers consist primarily of personal papers of Charles Benton Power, including incoming correspondence (1881-1953), diaries (1929-1949), minor financial records and legal documents, school notes and records (1880-1893), subject files, miscellany, and clippings.
The Charles Benton Power Estate Subgroup (1953-1960) includes general correspondence of co-administrators Blanche Mares and C.M. Wall, court papers; financial records, and subject files.
There are family subgroups for Power's wife Mabel Larson Power, his son Benton Power, his daughters Jane Power Tobin and Margaret Power Drum Carrick, and for the Flanagan Family.
There are also business subgroups for T.C. Power and Brother, T.C. Power Company, Benton Group of Mines, Benton Hardware Company, Benton Transportation Company, Big Sag Land and Livestock Company, Faith Mining Company, Helena Building and Realty Company, Phoenix Development Company, and Unit Petroleum Company.
This collection inter-mingles closely with the Thomas C. Power Papers (MC 55). The two collections should be used together, as many subgroups appear in both collections. See "Seperated Materials" under the Administrative Information below.
Arranged by subgroup and series. Some material housed in oversize folder in archives map case. See inventory below for more information.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
Artifacts transferred to Museum. See inventory below for more information
For other related material see the Guide to the Thomas Charles Power papers MC 55, and the Guide to the Thomas C. Power papers MC 55b, at the Montana Historical Society.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Power, Charles Benton, 1868-1953; Power, Thomas C. (Thomas Charles), 1839-1923
Fort Benton (Mont.)--Commerce; Fort Walsh (N.W.T.); Helena (Mont.)--Commerce; Missouri Headwaters State Park (Mont.); Neihart (Mont.)--Industries; Rock Creek Ranch (Wolf Creek, Mont.); Brownstone Quarry (Mont.); PN Ranch (Mont.); Rogers Pass (Mont.); Surprise Mining Claim (Mont.)
Aberdeen-Angus cattle--Montana; Quarries and quarrying--Montana; Steamboats--Missouri River
Montana; Ranching; Mines and Mineral Resources; Transportation
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- Charles B. Power
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - A (correspondents include Dan Allen, American National Bank, Roy E. Ayers), 1902-1946 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
    - Benton Baker, 1938-1951 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
    - Frayne Baker, 1944-1951 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
    - I.P. Baker (re early Missouri River steamboats), 1925 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
    - Morris A. Bealle (re his book on Georgetown University football), 1947 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
    - Blaine family (includes Major John, Ella, Louise), 1888-1909 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
    - Daniel Brereton (reminiscent letters and writings re his experiences in Montana), 1881-1945 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
    - Joseph W. Brown (re Chief Many Tail Feathers), 1926 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
    - B (correspondents include A.L. Babcock, Margaret C. Bach, Maggie C. Beattie, Ned Beebe, Belder-Evans Company, Effie Bennett, Bloedel-Donovan Lumber Mills, Mother Bonaventura, Cora Brant, W.J. Butler, Butte Mines Band), 1885-1941 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
    - Steve Carpenter, 1888-1935 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
    - Margaret and Ike, Earl of Carrick (Margaret Power's second husband; includes first Trans-Atlantic air mail service from Ireland; see also Margaret Power, Margaret Drum), 1939, 1947 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
    - Columbia University, Class of 1891 alumni (includes two circular letters from Dwight David Eisenhower), 1922-1931 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
    - A.B. Cook (re Wellington Rankin's race for governor), 1928 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
    - Isabella "Belle" Cory, 1891-1893 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
    - C (correspondents include John H. Charles, J. Burke Clements, J. A. Collette, Fritz Collins, Congressional Country Club, Joe Conway, Lydia Corwin, W.E. Cullen), 1886-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
    - Margaret Power Drum (letters from London; see also Margaret Power, Margaret Carrick), 1936 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
    - William D. Dwyer, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
    - D-E (correspondents include Victor Day, Wesley A. D'Ewart, I.W. Dixon, Mary L. Doane, Dong Goo Fun, Carl E. Dudley, Lulu Ellis, Lara P. Ellis, Cecelia D. Everett), 1890-1949 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
    - Bishop George J. Finnegan, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
    - First National Bank and Trust Company, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
    - May Flanagan, 1928-1946 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
    - May Franklin, 1892-1898 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
    - James H. Fullwood (London, England, re his early years at Fort McLeod and Fort Walsh), 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
    - F (correspondents include Catherine Fischer, Thomas C. Fitzpatrick, Mina [?] Thibault Flanagan, Geraldine Forbis, Arthur Ford, Lee M. Ford, Nathaniel Ford, Florence Fortune, Nannie Fortune), 1901-1949 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
    - Georgetown College classmates, 1888-1889, 1938 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
    - Robert Golden (in prison for theft from Rock Creek Ranch), 1944 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
    - G (correspondents include Bishop J.M. Gilmore, Gilpatrick Cabin Fund [Pioneer Cabin, Helena], Great Northern Railway Company), 1926-1950 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
    - John D. Holliday, 1900 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
    - Right Reverend Dr. Norbert C. Hoff, 1932-1934, 1940 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
    - Maud Van Buren Holme ("Old Squire"), 1891-1895, 1902 (Box-folder 1 / 30-33)
    - Norman B. Holter, 1888-1889, 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 34)
    - H-J (correspondents include [---] Hancock, Maud B. Harlow, Florence C. Hill, Clara H. Holter, Florence J. Holter, William H. Hunt, Ernest Immel, Ira Ingraham, C.J. Jones), 1885-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
    - John Walter Kearny, Jr.; Lucy Kearny (a few addressed to "Jane"), 1888-1897 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
    - Helen Keller (circular letters for American Foundation for the Blind), 1946-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
    - J.A. Kelton (proposing marriage), 1934 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
    - Mathilde Kessler, 1900-1902 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
    - Kinna family (includes C.J., Norma, P.), 1883-1889 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
    - Bror Kronstrand (Stockholm, Sweden), 1910, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
    - Mabel Larson [see also Mabel Larson Power], 1901-1902 (Box-folder 2 / 8-9)
    - Rae Lewis, 1894-1899 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
    - Amelia Bauces Lieber, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 2 / 11-13)
    - L (correspondents include Ulric LaChapelle, Thomas B. Lantry, Bessie O'Brien Lantry, Margaret Larson, Harry Lehr, Lewis and Clark County Clerk and Recorder, Louise Lieber, Joseph P. Lyman), 1893-1944 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
    - Gus MacDonell, 1891-1892, 1926 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
    - Leo Martin (Society of Jesus, includes information on Power house in Dubuque, Iowa), 1943, 1949 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
    - T.L. Martin, 1916, 1919 (Box-folder 2 / 17)
    - Clifford and Agnes McNamara, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 2 / 18)
    - Lurene Miller Meehan (re history of PN Ranch), 1934-1935 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
    - James Milford, 1894 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
    - Addie and Frances Murphy (daughters of John T. Murphy), 1894-1901 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
    - M (correspondents include L.E. Maguire, John W. Mahan, Harry Martin, Effie Bennett Martin, George N. McCabe, R. McCormick, Washington J. McCormick, Mary Livingston McDonald, F. McKinney, William L. McLaughlin, C.H. McLeod, Montana Children's Home and Hospital, Montana Newspaper Association, Montana Power Company, Mount St. Charles College, Mae Mount), 1883-1951 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
    - New York World's Fair, Inc., 1938-1939 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
    - Grace Nutting [?], 1884-1885, 1950 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
    - N (correspondents include Estelle Walsh Nagle, Ray Nagle, Notre Dame University), 1930-1950 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
    - Leo Orschel (re P.S. Donovan and Walter Lindsay), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 3 / 8)
    - O (correspondents include O'Connor for Senator, M.G. O'Malley), 1932, 1947 (Box-folder 3 / 9)
    - Hattie S. Pashley (re architectural work done on T.C. Power residence by Willet and Pashley), 1903, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 3 / 10)
    - Benton Power (re work at Hughesville mine, Georgetown College, visit to London, travel around the world), 1925-1931 (Box-folder 3 / 11-16)
    - Jane Power (re College of Sacred Heart, Dominican College, visit with Margaret in London; see also Jane Power Tobin), 1921-1939 (Box-folder 3 / 17-20)
    - John W. "Jack" Power (re army life), 1942-1944 (Box-folder 3 / 21)
    - Mabel Larson Power [see also Mabel Larson], 1903-1904 (Box-folder 3 / 22-23)
    - Mabel Larson Power, 1905-1914 (Box-folder 4 / 1-10)
    - Mabel Larson Power, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 5 / 1-4)
    - Margaret Power [see also Margaret Power Drum; Margaret Carrick], 1908, 1926, 1930 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
    - Mary G. Power (mother), 1907-1918 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
    - P-R (correspondents include Harry H. Parsons, Walter T. Parsons, May Bell Patenaude, Lucia Peary, Annie Howard Pendleton, William Power and Company, Wellington D. Rankin, Republican Party, J.G. Rex, J. Ritter, Sallie Roberts, Anita D. Rosencrans, Estelle Royce), 1888-1952 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
    - Society of Montana Pioneers, Sons and Daughters of Montana Pioneers (includes memorial on death of T.C. Power), 1923-1950 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
    - Elizabeth (Mrs. J.W.) Stewart (aunt), Margaret Stewart, 1926, 1935 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
    - S (correspondents include Saint Vincent Academy, James U. Sanders, James Willard Schultz, Hugh L. Scott, Christine Shannon, Lydia Corwin Sharpe, Celia Simmons), 1890-1943 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
    - Eleanor Blaine Thompson, 1895-1902 (Box-folder 5 / 11)
    - Tom Tobin, Jane Power Tobin (see also Jane Power), 1943-1948 (Box-folder 5 / 12)
    - Father J.G. Tougas, 1924-1939 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
    - E.B. Trail (re Missouri River steamboat history, includes typed copy of Benton log, 1881), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 14)
    - T (correspondents include Frederic Taylor, Ella H. Thatcher, Caroline Thornton, Butte H. Tipton), 1892-1947 (Box-folder 5 / 15)
    - Vaughan-Rhys family (includes Gwen, T.J., Hilma), 1939-1945 (Box-folder 5 / 16)
    - E.E. Wenner, 1928 (Box-folder 5 / 17)
    - Winifred Wyard, 1890-1892, 1900 (Box-folder 5 / 18-21)
    - W (correspondents include Elizabeth Duer Walker, Elizabeth "Lizzie" Wallace, Robert Bruce Wallace, Walsh for Senator Club, Father Weber, Nellie Darling Webster, Mamie C. Wheeler, Wong Ling), 1889-1950 (Box-folder 5 / 22)
    - Samuel B.M. Young (includes obituary), 1924, undated (Box-folder 5 / 23)
    - Unidentified, 1890-1951 (Box-folder 5 / 24)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (includes several long reminiscent letters), 1875, 1932-1951 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Daniel Brereton to Agnes McNamara, 1941 (Box-folder 6 / 2)
    - Open letters from Frank J. Edwards to O.M. Lanstrum re Helena politics, undated (Box-folder 6 / 3)
    - Arthur Ford to Nathaniel Ford (re death of T.C. Power), 1923 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
    - Fritz Haynes, 1949 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
  - Court Papers
    - Elizabeth Tuttle vs. [heirs of Peter McLear including Charles B. Power], 1933 (Box-folder 6 / 6)
  - Diaries
    - Diaries (many include weather clippings), 1929-1930, 1933-1938 (Box-folder 6 / 7-9)
    - Diaries [typed excerpts], 1939-1949 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - Financial Records
    - Banks: American National Bank, 1900-1914, undated (Box-folder 6 / 11)
    - Banks: statements of condition, B-S [scattered], 1883-1889 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
    - Bills: Montana Club, 1903 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
    - Bills: miscellaneous, 1913-1918 (Box-folder 6 / 14)
    - Household and personal expenses, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 6 / 15)
    - Ledger (personal), 1936-1952 (Box-folder 6 / 16)
    - Life insurance annuity, 1935 (Box-folder 6 / 17)
    - Taxes, 1944-1950 (Box-folder 6 / 18)
      RESTRICTED
  - School Notes and Records
    - Helena Public Schools report cards, 1880-1883 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
    - Georgetown College class notes and exams, 1883-1889 (Box-folder 7 / 2-4)
    - Georgetown College expenses, 1884-1888 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
    - Georgetown College report cards, miscellany, 1883-1888 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
    - Columbia College report cards, miscellany, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
    - Columbia Law School class notes, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 7 / 8-11)
    - Columbia Law School moot court cases, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
    - Columbia Law School miscellany, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
  - Subject File
    - Julian Anderson reception at Montana Club, 1938 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
    - Arcade Building, 1937 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
    - Spruille Braden, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
    - Broadwater Hotel, 1931, undated (Box-folder 8 / 4)
    - Chicago Motor Car Company (re Packard automobiles), 1907-1914 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
    - Dog pedigrees, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
    - Frank J. Edwards (includes letter to Franklin D. Roosevelt, article on Clark-Daly feud), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 8 / 7)
    - Elks Club (includes membership list, dues receipts, memorial service program, newsletter, clippings), 1898-1941 (Box-folder 8 / 8)
    - Arthur Ford (New York City civil engineer, son of Nathaniel Ford, T.C. Power's coachman), 1950 (Box-folder 8 / 9)
    - Fort Benton Centennial celebration, 1946 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
    - Grand juries in Helena, 1887-1888 (re identities of people in old photographs in newspaper), 1941 (Box-folder 8 / 11)
    - Founders Club Headwaters of the Missouri State Monument, 1950 (Box-folder 8 / 12)
    - Helena water bond election, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 8 / 13)
    - Henry and Larson Lumber Company, 1934 (Box-folder 8 / 14)
    - John D. Holliday death (partner in Escallier Sheep Company), 1939 (Box-folder 8 / 15)
    - Holter family (includes Norman B. Holter talk at Montana Children's Home and Hospital banquet), 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 16)
    - Margaret Larson's death (includes obituaries, sympathy letters, etc.), August 1924 (Box-folder 8 / 17)
    - Missouri River navigability hearing, 1946 (Box-folder 8 / 18)
    - Montana Historical Society, 1928-1929, 1952 (Box-folder 8 / 19)
    - Overland telegraph line history by William Simpson (includes early telegram), undated (Box-folder 8 / 20)
    - Benton Power's death (includes clippings, sympathy letters, lists of cards, etc.), March 1932 (Box-folder 8 / 21-24)
    - Charles B. Power residence: 309 North Ewing (includes construction bills for Howard Pew, William A. French and Company bills for furnishings), 1907-1908 (Box-folder 8 / 25-26)
    - Charles B. Power residence: 642 Dearborn (renovation and grounds blueprints) [Map Case], 1913 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Charles B. Power residence: 642 Dearborn (renovation estimates and bills: George H. Carsley, architect, miscellaneous, A-W), 1913 (Box-folder 8 / 27-29)
    - Charles B. Power residence: 642 Dearborn (furnishing bills: Marshall Field and Company; Blair Kinkaid, etc.), 1913-1914 (Box-folder 8 / 30-31)
    - Charles B. Power residence: 642 Dearborn (inventory), 1928 (Box-folder 8 / 32)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (correspondence with architects R.C. Reamer; Donovan and Rhoads), 1910-1913 (Box-folder 9 / 1-2)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (construction notes and specifications), 1910-1912 (Box-folder 9 / 3-4)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (blueprints by R.C. Reamer and by Donovan and Rhoads) [Map Case], 1911 (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (construction and furnishing bills, B-W), 1912-1913 (Box-folder 9 / 5-9)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (construction payrolls and board bills), 1912 (Box-folder 9 / 10)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (construction checkstubs), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 9 / 11)
    - Charles B. Power residence: Rock Creek Lodge north of Wolf Creek (Indian pictographs on ranch), 1926-1927 (Box-folder 9 / 12)
    - Mabel L. Power's death (sympathy letters, cards, etc.), July 1918 (Box-folder 9 / 13-15)
    - Margaret Power's marriage to Frank Goss Drum, 1928 (Box-folder 9 / 16)
    - Red Tomahawk, 1928, undated (Box-folder 9 / 17)
    - Rogers Pass controversy (re routing of Great Falls-Missoula highway), 1936-1938 (Box-folder 9 / 18)
    - Sesqui-Centennial exhibition (American independence), 1926 (Box-folder 9 / 19)
    - Travel: California, 1912 (Box-folder 9 / 20)
    - Travel: England and France (expenses), 1913 (Box-folder 9 / 21)
    - Travel: Jamaica, 1916, 1920 (Box-folder 9 / 22-23)
    - Vigilante Parade (includes lists of floats, clippings), 1939 (Box-folder 9 / 24)
    - Wedding to Mabel Larson (includes acceptances of invitations, trip expenses, lists of gifts, etc.), December 1902 (Box-folder 9 / 25-26)
  - Writings
    - "The First Aberdeen-Angus in Montana", 1949 (Box-folder 9 / 27)
    - "PN Ranch: historical data in connection therewith", circa 1950 (Box-folder 9 / 28)
  - Miscellany
    - Almost-engagement to daughter of Marcus Daly (unidentified note of congratulations), undated (Box-folder 10 / 1)
    - Birthday greetings, 1929-1940, undated (Box-folder 10 / 2)
    - Certificates (includes Columbia Law School degree, admission to Montana Bar, appointment as honorary colonel in Montana National Guard) [Map Case], 1893, 1940 (Oversize-folder 3)
    - Christmas gift lists, 1909-1920 (Box-folder 10 / 3)
    - Coat of arms, etc., 1923, 1931 (Box-folder 10 / 4)
    - Consecration of Cathedral of St. Helena, 1924 (Box-folder 10 / 5)
    - Deaths of friends (cards, etc.), 1924-1951 (Box-folder 10 / 6-7)
    - Dinner and dance programs, 1880s- 1890s (Box-folder 10 / 8)
    - Eulogies by Rev. D.B. Price, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 10 / 9)
    - Robert H. Fletcher outfitting brochures, undated (Box-folder 10 / 10)
    - Installations of Leo T. Martin, George J. Finnigan, Most Reverend Ralph Leo Hayes, Emmett J. Riley, 1921-1945 (Box-folder 10 / 11)
    - Invitations to weddings, dances, at-homes, etc., 1880s- 1940s (Box-folder 10 / 12-16)
    - Liquor price survey, 1936 (Box-folder 10 / 17)
    - Lists of capitalists, undated (Box-folder 10 / 18)
    - Montana Club membership list, 1919 (Box-folder 10 / 19)
    - Montana Liquor Control Board ration cards and residential permits, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 10 / 20)
    - Dan P. Mumbrue writings (includes "Carlsbad Caverns: A Description," "An Easter Thought," "Friends," "The Old Home Town," "Our Road," "Should I Be Afraid?"), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 11 / 1)
    - Poems (includes anonymous poem on Jeannette Rankin's vote against World War I, two poems by Scotty Sheriff on strike of sheep shearers, "In Montana: a Land of Contrasts," etc.), 1919-1946, undated (Box-folder 11 / 2)
    - Poems (political, mostly re Franklin D. Roosevelt), undated (Box-folder 11 / 3)
    - Poems (by Martin Maginnis re Japan, Ireland, missionaries), 1901, undated (Box-folder 11 / 4)
    - "A Railroad Real Estate Deal of Conscience: A Story of Sinister Financial Jobbery an Excellent Field for Investigations," by Secretary of the Interior James Rudolph Garfield, circa 1908 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
    - Recipes, undated (Box-folder 11 / 6)
    - St. Helena Cathedral musical programs, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 11 / 7)
    - General Terry's order to George Armstrong Custer [typescript copy], 1876 (Box-folder 11 / 8)
    - Wedding announcements from friends and relatives, 1884-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 9-10)
    - "Westward Ho to Fort Walsh in 1879" by George Shepherd, undated (Box-folder 11 / 11)
    - Miscellaneous (includes membership cards, tickets, programs, jury summons, etc.), 1889-1950, undated (Box-folder 11 / 12)
  - Clippings
    - Banks, 1926-1941 (Box-folder 11 / 13)
    - "Echoes from the distant past," by M.G. O'Malley [series of historical articles], 1941, 1947 (Box-folder 11 / 14)
    - Fort Benton buildings and history, 1929-1950 (Box-folder 11 / 15)
    - Helena buildings and history, 1920s- 1950s (Box-folder 11 / 16)
    - History (wide range of topics), 1920s- 1950s (Box-folder 11 / 17-18)
    - Mining, 1920s- 1950s (Box-folder 11 / 19)
    - Missouri River steamboats, 1909, 1924 (Box-folder 11 / 20)
    - Obituaries: A-Z, 1930s- 1950s (Box-folder 11 / 21)
    - People, 1930s- 1940s (Box-folder 11 / 22)
    - Politics, 1930s- 1940s (Box-folder 11 / 23)
    - Benton Power's auto accident which killed Thomas Nangle, December 1931 (Box-folder 11 / 24)
    - Thomas C. Power and T.C. Power and Brother, 1918-1927 (Box-folder 11 / 25)
    - Scenic, travel etc., 1926-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 26)
    - Weather, 1920s- 1950s (Box-folder 11 / 27)
- Charles B. Power Estate (co-administrators Blanche Mares and C.M. Wall)
  - General Correspondence
    - A-G (correspondents include Nancy Allinson, Bogy Mercantile Company, Columbia University Alumni Federation, First National Bank and Trust Company, May G. Flanagan, Joseph B. Gary, Guardian Life Insurance Company), 1953-1958 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
    - Paul Hollenstein, 1955 (Box-folder 12 / 2)
    - H-S (correspondents include Home Life Insurance Company, Mining Association of Montana, Walter Oehncke, Mrs. William Schimpf), 1953-1968 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
    - E.G. Toomey, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
    - T-U (correspondents include Thomas D. Tobin, Tri-City Oil Company, U.S. Internal Revenue Service), 1953-1967 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
    - C. Howard Walden, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 12 / 6)
    - C.M. Wall, 1958 (Box-folder 12 / 7)
  - Court Papers
    - Appointment of Thomas D. Tobin as guardian for Judith, Jane Lynn, and Thomas B. Tobin, 1950, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12 / 8)
    - Bequest receipts, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 12 / 9)
    - Claims filed against Estate, 1954 (Box-folder 12 / 10)
    - Pauline Ely Power vs Estate (and related cases), 1954-1959 (Box-folder 12 / 11)
    - Quiet title cases, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 12 / 12-13)